



REGAN RAVICHANDRAN (1) Featured | 7

Senior Consultant seeking roles in Software Development, Software Designing, Application Programming, Coding, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, Technical Support, Incident Management, SQL, Unix, PL/SQL, ODI (ETL)

Current Designation: Senior Consultant Application Development

Current Company: Virtusa Consulting Services Pvt. Ltd

Current Location: Chennai

Pref. Location: Pune, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Consultant, Team Lead/Tech Lead, Software Development, Software Designing, Application

Total Experience: 11 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 3 Months

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.

[Electronics/Telecommunication]

Programming, Coding, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, Technical Support, Incident

Management, Unix, PL/SQL, Oracle, Oracle Data Integrator

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 10-Dec-20 Last Modified: 10-Dec-20

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

#### Summary

10+ years of experience in application maintenance portfolio using CMM Methodology along with ITIL & Scrum Framework Deft in handling software projects from inception, requirement specifications, planning, designing, implementation, configuration management, documentation and closure with cross-cultural teams

Significant experience of working with clients, senior project managers and technical teams for executing projects Gained onsite exposure Birmingham and London, UK for 3 months each

An effective leader with proven abilities in leading teams during the project phase, training & guiding team members and enabling knowledge sharing among the team

### **Work Experience**

Virtusa Consulting Services Pvt. Ltd as Senior Consultant Application Development Oct 2019 to Till Date

Key Responsibilities:

Consulting with customers and other stakeholders about software system design and maintenance Involve in design, development, testing and implementation of the application

Perform system study and coordinating with team members for documentation, system design & integration, coding, application maintenance

Handle incidents, inconsistencies in functionality, interfaces and questionable operationsClient Standard Chartered

The bank provides clients with innovative solutions in transaction banking, corporate and project financing as well as a broad range of treasury products. On cash management, it provides a wide range of services to corporate and institutional clients to help them with payments and collections, information management, account services and liquidity management solutions.

Description

Legal compliance process or procedure is essential to ensure that the organization follows relevant laws, regulations and business rules. Customer?s data such as account details, transactions, etc. are extracted into files and are transferred to alternate server and are loaded onto the database schema which is processed by the system to perform the rules validation to ensure the compliance in regard to various aspects.

Responsibilities

Prepare Technical Specifications document based on the Solution & High-level design documents Implementing the codes onto pre-prod/production environment coordinating with Functional & Testing teams Provide guidance to team members

Handle defects and Quality assurance functions

SQL. PL/SQL. ODI Technologies involved Languages:

Operating System: Unix Database: Oracle

# **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

Collabera Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Bangalore, India

Senior Software Engineer

Key Responsibilities:

Handling design, development, testing and implementation of the application

Undertake system study and coordinating with team members for documentation

Analysing incidents, inconsistencies in functionality, interfaces and questionable operations

Project Title AML - Anti-Money Laundering Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

Client ANZ Bank

ANZ Bank is one of the 4 top tier banks in Australia, with operations also in New Zealand, Asia, Europe and North America. The partnership with IBM provides ANZ with increased capability to drive productivity and innovation across the Group, as well as improving its capacity to deal with the rapidly growing number of customers and transactions across the bank's branch, digital and mobile channels and support ANZ's regional expansion.

Description

The Anti-Money Laundering framework guides the ANZ approach to the detection & deterrence of money laundering activities which use or seek to use the bank's products or services. Transaction data of the customers and accounts are extracted into files on set frequency and are transferred to separate environment and are loaded onto respective schema which can be scrutinized by authorised business users to carry out the various checks such as due diligence, compliance, suspicious transactions, etc. as part of AML process.

Responsibilities

Preparing Micro design document based on the Solution & Macro design documents

Implementing the codes onto pre-prod/production environment

Provide guidance to team members

Ensuring Quality of the deliverables and handling incidents

Technologies involved Languages: SQL, PL/SQL

Operating System: Unix Database: Oracle

# Infosys Ltd as Technology Lead

Jan 2011 to Sep 2013

Infosys Ltd. Jan 2011 - Sep 2013

Chennai, India Technology Lead Key Responsibilities:

Provided leadership to the team members and resolved issues

Interacting with team members to ensure smooth progress of project work

Distinguished efforts for ensuring that the projects adhere to CMM standard

Successfully incorporated knowledge [technical, functional, etc.] management (KM) by encouraging & motivating team members to actively participate in such KMinitiatives

Conducting system study and coordinating with team members for documentation, system design & integration, coding, application maintenance, etc.

Delivering and implementing the project as per scheduled deadlines and extending post-implementation and maintenance support

Project Title Finacle, an Universal Banking Solution Apr 2011 - Sep 2013

Client T-Bank

Turkland Bank (T-Bank) is an extremely efficient and relatively small niche bank

that is able to offer various banking products and services to its clientele. T-Bank

concentrates its activities on foreign trade-oriented medium-sized companies and is continuously enhancing the scope of the banking services it offers to its clients

by broadening the correspondent banking network.

West Africa (MEA)

ATS support for banks in West Africa region, implemented with Finacle software as their banking solution provider. Description

Finacle is an universal banking solution created by Infosys to address the core banking, e-banking, Islamic banking, treasury, wealth management and CRM requirements of retail, corporate and universal banks.

Turkland bank has opted to implement Finacle for the core banking portfolio.

Banks in West Africa region had already incorporated Finacle as their banking solution and are being provided with support & maintenance by Infosys.

Responsibilities

Prepared Approach document based on the Solution & High level design documents

Implemented the customized codes coordinating with Functional & Testing teams

Provided guidance to team members

Handled defects, Project Management and Quality assurance functions

CMM methodology Implementation Anchor

Technologies involved Languages: SQL

Operating System: Unix Database: Oracle

#### SopraSteria Ltd as Senior Engineer

Apr 2004 to Dec 2010

SopraSteria Ltd. (formerly Xansa)

Apr 2004 - Dec 2010

Chennai, India Senior Engineer

Key Responsibilities:

Analyzing user needs and requirements to determine feasibility of design within time and cost constraints

Worked at:

Onshore centre at Birmingham, UK for a period of 3 months (March, April & May'06)

Client's (FSA) office at London, UK for a period of 3 months (September, October & November'07)

Built tracking automation module for the Inbound Gateway system's worklist, to reduce the manual effort - appreciated by the client

Monitoring and ensuring customer delivery during the transition period

Consulting with customers and other stakeholders about software system design and maintenance

Undertaking design & development, testing, debugging and troubleshooting of the application

Identifying, analyzing defects, questionable functions, inconsistencies in software functions, outputs, online screens and content

Facilitated implementation of ITIL framework and continuous improvement at Steria

Awarded hy FSA-customer as Team of the Year 2009 for outstanding performance among three too notch IT senice

or roughliner as treath or the treat 2000 for ealightness performance among three top hoter three tops

providers

Project Title Inbound Gateway (IG) Nov 2004 - Apr 2007

Client BT NTS, British Telecom

Description

IG is a grouping together of several applications under a common Web based front end. Central to the system is the management of customer orders and the reduction of manual activity by the ISTC (Inbound Services Technical Centre), which eases the process of order building for Telemarketing Numbers in OPS (another BT application called Order Processing System, built using mainframe technology). IG caters BT sales people to easily provide/build orders for new Telemarketing number needs, by offering different easily understandable front-end screens for different categories of Telemarketing numbers. Internally, the system automates various sub-processes involved in the Order building process using Oracle Workflow.

Responsibilities Handled Incidents & Problems Implemented Changes & Enhancements Prepared documents & reports

Technologies involved Languages: SQL, PL/SQL

Operating System: Unix Database: Oracle

Project Title Translation Manager (TM) Feb 2005 - May 2006

Client BT NTS, British Telecom

Description

TMis the system which controls, reports and translates information from Order Processing System (OPS) onto the Inbound Platforms (physical network). It performs Service Managed Automated Provisioning of network translations, and put them onto the BT network.

Responsibilities Handled Incidents & Problems Implemented Changes & Enhancements Out of Office Hours (OOH) Support (24/7) as well

Technologies involved Languages: Operating System: MS Windows SQL, PL/SQL, Visual Basic

Database: Oracle

Project Title Telex Jun 2006 - Apr 2007

Client British Telecom

Description

Telexis a combination of two modules namely INSPECTA and TACS. INSPECTA is a batch and on-line system that processes Telex calls going through the BT Telex exchanges and creates billing information.

TACS provides accounting reports for international Telex calls, which are passed to it from the Telex SPC exchanges.

Responsibilities Handled Incidents & Problems Prepared documents & reports

Technologies involved Languages: SQL, PL/SQL

Operating System: Unix Database: Oracle

Project Title ConnectPlus May 2007 - May 2008

Financial Services Authority (FSA) is an organization which regulates all the financial bodies operating inside the United Kingdom. It is an independent non-governmental body, which has been given statutory powers by the Financial Services and Markets Act 2000.

Description

^ Back to Top

# **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Bectronics/Telecommunication) from Madurai Kamaraj University (MKU) in 2003

^ Back to Top

## IT Skills

Skill Name MS WINDOWS, UNIX	Version Last Used	Experience
SQL and ORACLE PL/SQL		
Oracle, MS Access		
ODI		

^ Back to Top

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	
English					

J -			
Hindi			
Tamil			

^ Back to Top

## **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

## **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.